kaboompics.com 2019-10-05

# Free stock photos - Kaboompics

### Privacy Policy for Kaboompics

#### 1\. Introduction

Kaboompics is a service providing free stock photos to our users. We also share our knowledge and photo tips on our blog and through our newsletter. If you decide to receive exclusive free photo bundles, interesting news from the world of photography, and other entertaining information via our newsletter, you want to be sure that your personal data is secured. Our Privacy Policy guarantees that. We also want to explain how the data collected through the use of our website is being processed. Please remember that Kaboompics values each user and we would never share your personal information with third parties or breach your trust in any other way.

For the purposes of this policy, Kaboompics defines the term “Subscriber” as an entity with which Kaboompics has an established relationship (you have subscribed to our newsletter), and the term “Visitor” as an individual that visits our front-end website (for example www.kaboompics.com). Any information stored on Kaboompics platform is treated as confidential. All information is stored securely and is accessed by authorized personnel only. Kaboompics implements and maintains appropriate technical, security and organizational measures to protect Personal Data against unauthorized or unlawful processing and use, and against accidental loss, destruction, damage, theft or disclosure.

#### 2\. Collection and use

#### 2.1. General

The following sections cover the specifics of each of the two groups from which data is collected: website Visitors and Subscribers.

#### 2.2. Website Visitors

If you are a Visitor to our website only, and not a Subscriber to a newsletter, this section is relevant for you.

By visiting this website, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Data as described herein. If you do not agree with the terms set out herein, please do not visit this website. If required by applicable law, we will seek your explicit consent to process Personal Data collected on this website or volunteered by you. Kindly note that any consent will be entirely voluntary. However, if you do not grant the requested consent to the processing of your Personal Data, the use of this website may not be possible.

Kaboompics may collect, record and analyze information of Visitors to the website. We may record your IP address and use cookies. Kaboompics gathers data about visits to the website, including numbers of Visitors and visits, geo-location data, length of time spent on the site, pages clicked on or where Visitors have .

#### 2.3. Subscribers

In order to provide our Users with the specifically selected content and exclusive photos, Kaboompics collects email addresses. Data entered or transferred into Kaboompics by Users (Subscribers) such as texts, questions, contacts, media files, etc., remains the property of the User and may not be shared with a third party by Kaboompics without express consent from the User.

We use the newsletter to:

  * To establish a relationship with you;
  * To update you on changes to our services or products, including new promotions.

We are not going to share your email address with any other parties, and you have the right to withdraw your consent to the collection of Personal Information at any time by sending a written request to hello@kaboompics.com

We encourage you to learn and exercise your rights. You can find out more about GDPR on this website (https://gdpr-info.eu/)

#### 2.4. Facebook

If you provide Kaboompics with your social media details, Kaboompics may retrieve publicly available information about you from social media. Such Personal Data contains your IP address, first and last name, your postal and email address, your telephone number, your job title, data for social networks, your areas of interest, interest in Kaboompics products, and certain information about the company you are working for (company name and address), as well as information as to the type of relationship that exists between Kaboompics and yourself.

#### 3\. Purpose of processing personal data

Kaboompics uses the collected data to communicate with Visitors, to customize content for Visitors, and to improve the website by analyzing how Visitors navigate.

#### 3.1. Sharing personal data

Kaboompics may also share such information with service vendors or contractors in order to provide a requested service or transaction or in order to analyze the Visitor behavior on its website.

#### 4\. Links to other sites

Please be aware that while visiting our site, Visitors can follow links to other sites that are beyond our sphere of influence. Kaboompics is not responsible for the content or privacy policy of these other sites but we make sure that all our links are from reliable sources.

#### 5\. Persons Under 18

The Website is not marketed toward persons under the age of 18. If Company discovers that it has inadvertently collected Personal Information about individuals under the age 18, it will promptly delete such information. Of course, if are below the age of 18, you can browse Kaboompics freely. You won’t find here any inappropriate content. However, if you’d like to subscribe to our newsletter, we shall need your parents’ consent!

### Cookie Policy for Kaboompics

_What Are Cookies?_

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or 'break' certain elements of the sites functionality.

For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on HTTP Cookies.

_How We Use Cookies?_

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

_Disabling Cookies_

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

_The Cookies We Set_

  * Site preferences cookies

In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences.

_Third Party Cookies_

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Analytics page.

  * Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase.

  * We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including; {List the social networks whose features you have integrated with your site?:12}, will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

_More Information_

However if you are still looking for more information then you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods:

Email: hello@kaboompics.com
